Denzel Edwards

(289) 923-8480 | Denzelsedwards@gmail.com | Website | GitHub | LinkedIn

Dear Hiring Manager,

During my 3 years of experience as a full-stack Web Developer, I have developed both the functional and aesthetic components of my various websites. I believe I can make an immediate impact on your organization with my unique blend of skills and passion.

As a recent university computer engineering graduate, my professional experience includes using my knowledge of programming languages such as HTML, CSS and JavaScript, to create versatile applications, websites and programs. I have further experience with using SQL and NoSQL databases, jQuery, Node.js, React and Redux.

Being a part of organizations like the National Society of Black Engineers and Ryerson Engineering Society have given me skills in logical decision-making regarding software best practices, as well as teamwork, and critical thinking skills. As well as an aptitude for designing, planning and communication. I believe my initiative and desire to learn will help me contribute and make me a great fit for this position with your company.

Thank you for your time and I look forward to having an interview with you.

Sincerely,
Denzel Edwards

Denzel Edwards

(289) 923-8480 | Denzelsedwards@gmail.com | Website | GitHub | LinkedIn

Web developer with a passion for building efficient, aesthetically pleasing websites from the front to the back end. Skilled at conceptualizing, designing and implementing clean and efficient software while following the industry standard and continually growing.

Skills

- Experience with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Experience working with React, Redux Node.js, jQuery and ASP.NET.
- Experience in working with SQL and NoSQL.
- Experience with Java, C, Python, and Assembly Language.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office and Photoshop.
- Ability to handle multiple tasks concurrently and to meet deadlines.
- Exemplary problem-solving skills; able to identify problems and implement corrective processes.
- Ability to thrive in a team atmosphere, making individual contributions to challenging projects.
- Knowledge of basic PC architecture and digital systems

Education

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING / RYERSON UNIVERSITY

GRADUATION: JUNE 2020 - DEAN'S LIST 2019-2020

Experience

- Cinnamon A cafe website using Mongo, Express, React and Node.
- Planet Store A store made using MERN stack where you can purchase different planets.
- Weather Watch An app that let's you checkout the weather of cities around the world.
 Node.js, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- <u>Dice Game</u> A dice game where the player with the higher number is the winner JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- <u>Copy Me</u> A web designed memory game where the user has to remember the moves made by the computer to advance to the next level. Made using CSS, HTML and JavaScript.
- Maze Game Two-Dimensional Multiplayer Maze Game using Java.

RELEVANT ACADEMIC PROJECTS:

- Smart City Application Platform: Waste Management Application that uses sensors located in bins that sends how full they are to a central raspberry pi to be scheduled for pickup and displayed on a website for clients to see. [Python, HTML, CSS]
- Cafeteria Mock-up Cafeteria Mock-up design using React. [React]
- Online Cafeteria Online Cafeteria website made with asp.net. [ASP.NET]
- Media Center Project Using the MCB1700 board, uVision. Features include a photo gallery
 capable of displaying various bmp files, an mp3 player that plays streaming audio/mp3 tracks
 from the PC, and a game center with two different games the user can play. [C]

CURRENT

CONSULTING RESEARCHER FOR AN INDEPENDENT PROFESSIONAL CONSULTANT

- Researched case law and societal impacts of various human rights issues.
- Created comprehensive reports, reviews and summaries on my findings.

SEPTEMBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

HUMAN RIGHTS SERVICES ASSISTANT/ RYERSON UNIVERSITY

- Created Case lists for human rights issues using Excel and Google Sheets while researching and reflecting them against past legal precedents.
- Assist with the design and facilitation of assessment methods for events and initiatives.
- Helped organize and coordinate the case list for all human rights issues at Ryerson.

JUNE 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

COMPUTER IT ASSISTANT / FAMILY LIFE CENTRE'S COMPUTER LITERACY

- Taught computer literacy skills and developed curriculum's on various social media platforms, companies and computer technical skills to aid in the learning of computer proficiency.
- Completed repairs, troubleshooting, maintenance and assembling of computers.

APRIL 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

SEAFOOD CLERK / LOBLAWS

• Independently cleaned, took care of and organized the seafood department while serving customers and maintaining excellent customer service.

MAY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2019

SALES ASSOCIATE / NATIONAL SPORTS

- Helped customers while creating a welcoming environment for customers.
- Within a team, maintained a clean and organized establishment.
- Served customers within a timely manner under high customer volume and output demand daily.

AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2018

SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGEMENT / TRUE2SOUL NETWORK

- Updated and managed the twitter media account to promote the True2Soul brand network.
- Corresponded and worked in a team with the other members of the social media team.